ASHWINI VASUDEVAN

PROFILE INFO

A talented and enthusiastic PhD student, working as a Senior research fellow (SRF) at the Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences (ILBS) under fellowship (ITR- Innovation Translational Research category). Skilled in tissue engineering based scaffold fabrication, primary liver cells isolation organoid spheroid culture. Holding a strong graduation record in the specialized sectors of biotechnology and medical nanotechnology.

CONTACT INFO



9884690088



ashwinivasudevan@yahoo.com



Present address – 44B/9 Numberdar apartment, Akhara road, Kishangarh, New Delhi, 110070

Permanent address- No.1/272 Raja Rathinam street, Vandalur, Chennai.



https://www.linkedin.com/in/a shwini-vasudevan-030855139/



https://twitter.com/Ash_wineee

MY SKILLS

- Cell culture handling &
- maintenance Isolation of Primary Liver cells and culture
- Organoid culture
- 3D printing
- Electrospinning
- Nanoparticle synthesis
- Small animal handling
- * Small animal Blood and organ

collection

- · Small animal Ex-vivo perfusion
- · Small animal surgeries
- Western Blot
- Immunohistochemistry
- Immunofluorescence and confocal imaging
- RNA & DNA Extraction,PCR, RTPCR
- Plasmid isolation and Protein

Purification

EDUCATION HISTORY

Master of Technology 2018-2020 Medical Nanotechnology

SASTRA deemed to be University, Thanjavur. Cumulative Grade Point Average (CGPA)-7.5

Bachelor of Technology 2014-2018 Biotechnology Specialization in Cancer Biotechnology

Institute of Science and Technology, Vandalur, Chennai. Cumulative Grade Point Average (CGPA)-8.88

Sri Vishwa Vidyalaya Mat Hr.

B. S. Abdur Rahman Crescent

sec. school, Chennai, Higher Secondary School

2014

Higher secondary examination percentage-86.9%

Sri Vishwa Vidyalaya Mat Hr.

sec. school, Chennai, Secondary School

2012

Secondary school leaving certificate examination percentage- 92.6%

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Research Fellow

09' 2022- Present

ICMR funded project ,ITR category (Innovation and Translational Research).

ILBS, New Delhi.

Junior Research Fellow 2020- 2022

DST - ASEAN funded project

Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences (ILBS), New Delhi.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Selected for ICMR-SRF fellowship (2022) under the Innovation and translational research (ITR) category
- Summer research fellowship at "ICMR-National Institute of Immunohematology (Department of Hematogenetics)" by Indian Academy of science during the months of May-July 2019 under the guidance of Dr. Malay Mukherjee.
- Qualified GATE BT 2018 Examination

PROJECTS

- Currently working on ICMRfunded project, 'To prepare ECM based Electrospun scaffolds for liver regeneration in acute injury models' at the liver physiology lab, ILBS.
- Worked as JRF and completed a DST funded project entitled

- "Development of Nanoengineered Liver
 Scaffold: A Novel Device for Ex vivo Drug ScreeningApplications" in ILBS.
- Worked on developing liver-on-chip microfluidic devices with primary hepatocyte spheroids in ILBS.
- Worked on a project entitled "Radiationinduced fibrosis and epigenetic modifications involved in it" during my Master's dissertation in Radiation Biology Laboratory at SASTRA.
- Summer Internship project on "Screening Techniques for Thalassemia" at the National Institute of Immunohematology, Mumbai
- Worked on a project entitled "Isolation and Purification of Lectin from Pisum Sataivum and Vigna angularis" during my Bachelor's dissertation at the Life science Research Laboratory, Crescent University, Chennai.
- Performed "Purification of Flag-FOXP3
 plasmid" in Life science Research
 Laboratory at Crescent university,
 Chennai.

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. 'Evolution of Electrospinning in Liver Tissue Engineering' Vasudevan, A., Tripathi, D. M., Venugopal, Sundarrajan, S., Ramakrishna, S., & Kaur, S. (2022). Evolution Electrospinning Tissue of in Liver Biomimetics. Engineering. 7(4), 149.https://doi.org/10.3390/biomimetics70 40149. I.F (3.74) Citations = 6
 - 2.Kaur S, Kaur I, Rawal P, Tripathi DM, <u>Vasudevan A</u>. Non-matrigel scaffolds for organoid cultures. Cancer Lett. 2021;504:58-66.

http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.canlet.202 1.01.025. I.F (9.7) Citations= 29

3.Primary Hepatocyte Isolation and Cultures: Technical Aspects, Challenges and Advancements. Kaur I, <u>Vasudevan A</u>, Kaur S, Rawal P, Tripathi DM, January 2023, Bioengineering10(2):131. 10.3390/bioengineering10020131. I.F (5) Citations=

- 4. Chemically Modified Dipeptide Based Hydrogel Supports Three-Dimensional Growth and Functions of Primary Hepatocytes. S Biswas, Vasudevan A, N Yadav, P Rawal, I Kaur, Tripathi DM, Kaur S. August 2022. ACS Applied Bio Materials. DOI: 10.1021/acsabm.2c00526. I.F (3.25) Citations= 2
- 5. Mangifera indica and Mangifera zeylanica: Perspectives on medicinal properties, therapeutic applications and potential uses as anticancer epigenetic drugs. February 2022. DOI: 10.3892/ije.2022.10
 I Selvakumar, Vasudevan A, P Nirmal. I.F (4.86) Citations = 2

6.Ashwin V, Nilotpal M and et al., Liver Extracellular matrix-based Nanofiber scaffolds for the culture of primary hepatocytes and drug screening' (Under Revision ACS Biomaterial science and engineering)

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

 Research work selected under the 'BAJPAI SAHA student award category' for paper presentation under the title 'Fabrication of Extracellular matrix-based nano scaffolds to support functional hepatocytes' **Ashwini Vasudevan**, Indu Sharma, Impreet Kaur, Sourabh Ghosh, Jayram Reddy, Subramanian Sundarrajan, Seeram Ramakrishna, Dinesh M Tripathi, Savneet Kaur. at the 'International SBOAI Biomaterial Conference **BIOREMEDI**, Dec 2022-AT IIT-Guwahati.

- Research work presented as poster at the European Association for the Study of the Liver (EASL) Under the title 'Liver Matrix-based Electrospun Nano scaffolds for Improved Viability and Functionality of Primary hepatocytes in Culture' Ashwini Vasudevan, Indu Sharma, Impreet Kaur, Sourabh Ghosh, Jayram Reddy, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shiv K Sarin, Dinesh M Tripathi, Savneet Kaur. EASL, London, June, 2022
- Research work selected for the Young Investigator category, at the European Association for the Study of the Liver (EASL) Under the title 'Skin-decellularized matrix-derived microgels accelerate 3D cultures of functional primary hepatocyte spheroids in vitro' EASL, Vienna, Austria, 2023

REFERENCES

Dr Savneet Kaur

Associate professor Liver physiology and vascular biology lab,

Molecular and cellular medicine department,

Institute of Liver and Biliary Sciences

Mail: savykaur@gmail.com

Dr. Neesar Ahmed

Assistant Professor (sr. Gr.),

Department of Biotechnology, B.S.Abdur Rehman Institute of Scienceand Technology,

Vandalur, Chennai

Mail: neesar.sls@crescent.education.